Guide to the James R. Houck papers.
Houck, James R. papers.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
James R. Houck papers.
14-7-4112
J. R. Houck
69 cubic feet.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Papers of James Houck, currently awaiting processing.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Jim Houck is the Principal Investigator for the Infrared Spectrograph (IRS) instrument on Spitzer, the Space Infrared Telescope Facility formerly called SIRTF. Spitzer was launched on August 25, 2003, and is the fourth and last of NASA's Great Observatories, the others being Hubble Space Telescope (HST), Gamma Ray Observatory (GRO), and Advanced X-ray Astronomy Facilities (AXAF). Jim pioneered the use of mid-infrared spectrometers to determine the physical conditions inside a wide variety of astronomical objects from the giant planet Jupiter to distant galaxies. Early in his career he built infrared instruments launched on sounding rockets for brief, five minute peaks at the sky from above the atmosphere. Among the results from that work were the first discovery of the very high luminosities of star forming regions in our galaxy. These results were challenged in the literature until they were solidly confirmed by the Infrared Astronomical Satellite (IRAS) more than ten years later. Jim was a member of the science team that launched IRAS in 1983. In addition to IRAS and IRS, Jim also led the Cornell development of the state-of-the-art instrumentation for the 5-meter telescope at the Palomar Observatory. The first major instrument developed at Cornell for this site was SpectroCam, a thermal infrared camera and spectrograph operating near the diffraction limit of the telescope.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Papers of James Houck, currently awaiting processing.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Houck, J. R.; Houck, James Richard, 1940-
Subjects:
Astronomy.; Astronomy
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. General Documents
Series II. Correspondence Regarding SIRTF (Space Infrared Telescope Facility) and IRS (Infrared Spectrograph)
Series III. Palomar Related Material
Series IV. Shuttle Infrared Telescope Facility (SIRTF)
Series V. NASAmail
Series VI. IRS (Infrared Spectrometer)
Series VII. IRAS (Infrared Astronomy Satellite)
Series VIII. Jim Houck's Lear and C-141 Data
Series IX. Gemini Telescope
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. General Documents
  - Miscellaneous Papers, Expression (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Final Grant Report for NASA-Ames Grant, 1984-11-1987-09 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Supplements to NASA Grant, 1984-07-01-1986-09-30 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Invoices and Correspondence with Wallace Instruments, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Papers Regarding NASA Grant, 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Papers Regarding NASA Grant, 1985-1989 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Papers Regarding NASA Grant, 1987-1989 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Papers Regarding NASA Grant, 1984-1987 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous Papers, 1985-1989 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Emails and Invoices, 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Emails and Invoices, 1986-1990 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - SIRTF Science Working Group Minutes and Appendices, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - SIRTF Science Working Group Appendices, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - IRS Kickoff Review, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Budgets and Estimates, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Rockwell International Proposal, 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Negotiation Summary for IRS Experiment, 1990-1992 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Budget Concerns and Postponement of Experiment, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Budget Expansion Requests, 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Experiment Technicals and Phase Budgets, 1987-1989 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Periodic Financial Reports, 1987-1991 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - SIRTF Contractor Financial Management Report, 1988-1991 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Ball SIRTF-IRS Contract Pricing, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Subcontract for Experiment Implementation, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Statement of Work for IRS Phase I, 1987-1990 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Contracts, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Radiation Dosimetry Reports, 1990-1993 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Electronic Equipment and Cabling Design and Fabricating Requirements and Processing Techniques Vol I, 1988-08-22 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Electronic Equipment and Cabling Design and Fabricating Requirements and Processing Techniques Vol II, 1990-04-02 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Electronic Equipment and Cabling Design and Fabricating Requirements and Processing Techniques Vol III, 1983-09-12 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - SIRTF Telescope Facility/Science Instruments Interface Requirements, 1987-04 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Ames Research Center RFP Papers, 1986-06 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - SIRTF Tech Review #1, 1987-09 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - SIRTF Tech Review #2, 1987-09 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Meeting Agenda and Graphs, 1987-12-08 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Infrared Array Camera (IRAC) Instrument Requirements Review, 1987-12-09 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - SIRTF Instrument Requirements Review, 1987-12-10 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    Note on folder: Dark current is 16 not 30 e^-/sec (measured) QE 18 to 23% fum 4.5-to-25 um
  - Detector Technology Assessment Review, 1990-05-02 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence and Graphs, 1990-1991 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Fax Correspondence and Graphs, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence and Graphs, 1990-1992 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence and Graphs, 1990-1991 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence and Graphs, 1991-1992 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Grant Proposal, 1990-1993 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Jet Propulsion Laboratory (JPL) Contract Modifications, 1990-1992 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Jet Propulsion Laboratory (JPL) Contract Correspondence and Misc, 1991-1993 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - SIRTF Contract, 1990-04-11 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - JPL SIRTF Documents, 1990-10 (Box 6)
    Product Assurance, Project Policies, Science Requirements, Mission Requirements, EEIS Requirements, Fault Protection Requirements, Flight System Requirements, IRS Interface Requirements, IandT Requirements, Telescope and Spacecraft, Product Assurance
  - Study and Cost Plan Revision, 1986-11 (Box 6)
  - IRS Tech/Management/Cost Proposal, 1983-12 (Box 6)
  - IRS Tech/Management/Cost Proposal, 1986-07 (Box 6)
  - IRS Tech/Cost Proposal, 1987-09 (Box 7)
  - SIRTF IRS Phase B Proposal, 1990-10 (Box 7)
  - JPL Software Management Standards Package Level II, 1988-12 (Box 7)
  - SIRTF Exhibits Table of Contects, 1990-10-26 (Box 7)
  - Miscellaneous, 1986-09-22 (Box 7)
  - Flight Systems Safety Requirements, 1988-11 (Box 7)
  - SIRTF Spectroscopy Phase A Proposal, 1994-05 (Box 7)
  - OSP Sourcebook, 1994-06 (Box 7)
    Infrared Projects Sourcebook on Quality and Reliability Engineering, Strategies on Production, and Getting it right the first time
  - Expense Reports, 1994-1999 (Box 7)
  - IRS Cost Statements, 1986-11-1990-4 (Box 7)
  - Various SIRTF Packets, 1996-1999 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - SIRTF Spacecraft Conceptual Design Description, 1991-05 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - IRS Instrument Design Description, 1991-11 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - The M3 Proposal, 1993-05 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1994-12 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Space News Marketing Supplement, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - SIRTF System Study Final Report, 1995-04-01 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Miscellaneous Reports, 1995-1998 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - NAR Materials, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - SIRTF NAR Report to the PMC, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Impurity Band Conduction Hybrid Arrays For SIRTF, 1989-03-1992-10 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Miscellaneous Packets, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Multiband Imaging Photometer for the SIRTF, 1993-04-1995-04 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Phase C/D Implementation Plan Vol 2- Cost Plan, 1997-09-1997-11 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Linux Installation Guide, 1992-1994 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - SIRTF/IRS Meeting Minutes and Reports, 1991-02-13 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - SIRTF/IRS Plans and Reports, 1990-12-12 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Change Proposal for DSI Filter Procurement, 1999-01 (Box 25)
  - Phase C/D Implementation Plan Vol 2- Cost Plan, 1997-09-20 (Box 25)
  - Proposal for IRS Phase C/D, 1997-11 (Box 25)
  - Proposal for Co-Investigator for Planetary Science- Phase C/D, 1998-04-2002-01 (Box 25)
  - Proposal for IRS Work Re-Phasing, 1997-11 (Box 25)
  - Proposal for IRS Work Re-Phasing, 1997-11 (Box 25)
  - Proposal for IRS Phase C/D, 1997-11 (Box 25)
  - Phase C/D Implementation Plan Vol 2- Cost Plan, 1997-09-20 (Box 25)
  - Proposal for Co-Investigator for Planetary Science- Phase C/D, 1998-04-2002-01 (Box 25)
  - Proposal for SIRTF/IRS Phase B Study, 1996-10-01-1998-03-31 (Box 25)
  - Photos and Transparencies: VY Ca Maj 07^n 18^m 51^s -25 34.5, Undated (Box 31, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous Charts, Undated (Box 31, Folder 10)
    Found among multiple folders with star coordinates, but could not be related to these folders
  - Charts and Photos: W3 2^hr 21^m 52^s S+61 52' 30", Undated (Box 31, Folder 11)
    Folder kept for notes
  - Miscellaneous Charts, Undated (Box 31, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous Charts, Undated (Box 31, Folder 13)
  - Nicolet Digital Oscilloscopes, Undated (Box 31, Folder 14)
  - Catalogs and Journals, 1980 (Box 31, Folder 15)
  - Notebooks: D. Briotta, George Gull, 1983 (Box 31, Folder 16)
  - Notebooks: Graham Pugh, T. Roellig, 1983 (Box 31, Folder 17)
  - Notebooks: Bob Reed, 1975 (Box 31, Folder 18)
  - Notebooks: W.J. Forrest, 1977 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Notebooks: W.J. Forrest, 1978-1979 (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Research Proposals, 1987-1993 (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Research Proposals, 1988-1989 (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Research Proposals, 1987-1989 (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - Research Proposals, 1987-1990 (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - Research Proposals, 1987-1990 (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - Research Proposals, 1984-1993 (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - Contract Statements U25-8396, 1994-1995 (Box 32, Folder 9)
  - Contract Statements U25-8532, 1992 (Box 32, Folder 10)
  - Ball Labs SER's, 1989-1990 (Box 32, Folder 11)
  - Monthly Operations Statements U25-8486, 1987-1988 (Box 32, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous Installation Guides, 1986-1987 (Box 32, Folder 13)
  - Miscellaneous Installation Guides, 1986-1990 (Box 32, Folder 14)
  - Miscellaneous Papers, Undated (Box 32, Folder 15)
  - Miscellaneous Papers and Computer Code, 1989-1990 (Box 32, Folder 16)
  - Miscellaneous Papers and Computer Code, 1985-1988 (Box 32, Folder 17)
  - Miscellaneous Proposals, 1978-08-01-1982-10-31 (Box 32, Folder 20)
  - Miscellaneous Proposals, 1984-11-01-1985-10-31 (Box 32, Folder 21)
  - Miscellaneous Proposals, 1983-11-01-1987-10-31 (Box 32, Folder 22)
  - Miscellaneous Proposals, 1985-07-01-1988-06-30 (Box 32, Folder 23)
  - Far-Infrared Line Emission from the Galaxy, 1985-01 (Box 32)
  - One Millimeter Continuum Observations of Extra Galactic Thermal Sources, 1981 (Box 32)
  - Miscellaneous Proposals, 1985-07-01-1993-10-31 (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous Proposals, 1982-07-01-1987-06-30 (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous Proposals, 1982-11-01-1983-10-31 (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous Proposals, 1983-10-01-1986-09-30 (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous Proposals, 1982-07-01-1984-10-31 (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous Proposals, 1978-10-01-1985-10-31 (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous Proposals, 1985-11-01-1987-10-31 (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous Proposals, 1985-07-01-1988-06-30 (Box 33, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous Proposals, 1982-10-01-1984-09-30 (Box 33, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous Proposals, 1978-10-01-1986-09-30 (Box 33, Folder 10)
  - Paper: Very Large Structures in the Universe, Undated (Box 33, Folder 11)
  - Paper: Instrument Descriptions, 1988 (Box 33, Folder 12)
  - Paper: The Large-Scale Structure of the Universe, Undated (Box 33, Folder 13)
  - Paper: The Large-Scale Structure of the Universe, 1979 (Box 33, Folder 14)
  - Paper: Existence and Nature of Dark Matter in the Universe, 1987 (Box 33, Folder 15)
  - Paper: Very Low Mass Stars, 1987 (Box 33, Folder 16)
  - Paper: The Origin of Galaxies, 1970 (Box 33, Folder 17)
  - Paper: Voyager 2 in the Uranian System: Imaging Science Results, 1986 (Box 33, Folder 18)
  - Paper: Origin of the Solar System, 1988 (Box 33, Folder 19)
  - Miscellaneous Papers, Undated (Box 33, Folder 20)
  - Galileo: Exploration of Jupiter's System, Undated (Box 33, Folder 21)
  - Various Research Related Proposal Forms, 1996 (Box 33, Folder 22)
  - N/A- Budgets, Title Page, Miscellaneous, 1996-1998 (Box 33, Folder 23)
  - Proposal for Co-Investigator for Planetary Science, 1996-1998 (Box 33, Folder 24)
  - Miscellaneous Proposals, 1996-1998 (Box 33, Folder 25)
  - SIRTF Mass LIENS, 1996 (Box 33, Folder 26)
  - Infrared Source Cross-Index First Edition, 1987-04 (Box 33)
  - Astronomy 102/104: Our Solar System Reader by Jim Houck, Undated (Box 33)
  - Astronomy 102/104: Our Solar System Reader by Jim Houck, Undated (Box 33)
  - Instructor's Manual for Astronomy: The Cosmic Journey Third Edition by John L. Safko, 1985 (Box 33)
  - Flight Systems Section 313, 1996 (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Proposal for Atmospheric Infrared Sounder (AIRS), 1990 (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - SIRTF Program Miscellaneous, 1999 (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Presentation of AXAF Science Instruments, 1985 (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - High Resolution Imaging Spectrometer (HIRIS), 1989 (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - HEAO Project Task Management Plan, Undated (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - HRC (High Resolution Camera) on the (Advanced X-Ray Astrophysics Facility) Proposal, 1985-1993 (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - SIRTF IRS/MIPS Presentation, Undated (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous (emails, progress reports, presentation slides), 1998-1999 (Box 34, Folder 9)
  - NASA Education Materials, 1995 (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - Lab Notebooks: KAO Flights, 1981 (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - Lab Notebooks: KAO Flights, 1981-1982 (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - Lab Notebooks: KAO Flights, Undated (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - Lab Notebooks: KAO Flights, Undated (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous Data, Undated (Box 35, Folder 6)
    Includes data and graphs, tabulated folders, graph paper of data, envelopes of data, and more
  - Miscellaneous Data, Undated (Box 35, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous Photos, 1976-1979 (Box 35, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous Data, Undated (Box 35, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous Data, Undated (Box 35, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous Data, Undated (Box 35, Folder 11)
    Note on folder: Black Bodies
  - Miscellaneous Data, 1977-06 (Box 35, Folder 12)
    Note on folder: Ave Spectra
  - Miscellaneous Data, 1975-10-30-1975-10-31 (Box 35, Folder 13)
    Note on folder: 1 Jupiter #129
  - Miscellaneous Data, Undated (Box 35, Folder 14)
  - Miscellaneous Data, Undated (Box 35, Folder 15)
  - Miscellaneous Data, Undated (Box 35, Folder 16)
  - Miscellaneous Data, Undated (Box 35, Folder 17)
  - Miscellaneous Data, Undated (Box 35, Folder 18)
  - Miscellaneous Data, Undated (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous Data, Undated (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous Data, Undated (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous Data, Undated (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - DITS Photos and Materials, 1988 (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - Ball Mechanism Study, 1988-1989 (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - IRS Slides, 1983 (Box ?)
  - Atomic Viewgraphs, 1992 (Box ?)
  - Infrared General, 1979 (Box ?)
  - IRS Slides, 1982 (Box ?)
  - Miscellaneous Slides, Undated (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - Presentation Materials, 1991 (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - Meeting Materials, 1985 (Box 37, Folder 5)
  - Bahcall Presentation, 1991 (Box 37, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous Talk Materials, 1992 (Box 37, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous Talk Materials, 1984 (Box 37, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous Talk Materials, 1976-1983 (Box 37, Folder 9)
  - Infrared Spectrometer Status, 1991-03 (Box 37, Folder 10)
  - Detector Review, 1989-07 (Box 37, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous Materials/WIRE, 1992 (Box 37, Folder 12)
  - CAPPS Review, 1990 (Box 37, Folder 13)
  - IRS Viewgraphs, 1992 (Box 37, Folder 14)
  - IRAS Press Clips, 1983 (Box 37, Folder 15)
  - Paris and London Viewgraphs, 1986 (Box 37, Folder 16)
  - IRAS Slides, Undated (Box 37, Folder 17)
  - ZODY Viewgraphs, Undated (Box 37, Folder 18)
  - Black Paint' Paper Materials, Undated (Box 37, Folder 19)
  - Miscellaneous Notes and Transparencies, Undated (Box 37, Folder 20)
  - Hi Res' Paper Notes, 1982 (Box 37, Folder 21)
  - Faint Galaxies Notes and Transparencies, 1985-05-01-1985-05-03 (Box 37, Folder 22)
  - IRAS Photos, Undated (Box 37, Folder 23)
  - IRAS Prints, Undated (Box 37, Folder 24)
  - Miscellaneous Photos, Undated (Box 37, Folder 25)
  - Viewgraphs, Undated (Box 37, Folder 26)
  - Space Sciences Building Photographs, 1981-08 (Box 37, Folder 27)
  - Pittsburgh Talk: Carbon Stars and Planetaries, 1982-04-23 (Box 37, Folder 28)
  - Photos: LAM Grating, Undated (Box 37, Folder 29)
  - Transparencies: Supernovae Echo, 1983-1985 (Box 37, Folder 30)
  - Photos: LEAR Jet, Mauna Kea, Kitt Peak, 1973 (Box 37, Folder 31)
  - Photos: Misc. Rockets, Undated (Box 37, Folder 32)
  - Photos: Mt. Pleasant, Undated (Box 37, Folder 33)
  - Misc. Charts and Results, Undated (Box 37, Folder 34)
  - SPIE (The International Society for Optical Engineering) Talk Washington D.C., 1981-04-21 (Box 37, Folder 35)
  - Noordwisk Meeting Notes, 1985 (Box 37, Folder 36)
  - Focus Slide and Pen Mount Notes, Undated (Box 37, Folder 37)
  - SPIE (The International Society for Optical Engineering) Documents, Undated (Box 37, Folder 38)
  - Correspondence, 1980 (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Fuertes Observatory Documents, 1970-1971 (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - LEAR Jet and C-141 Documents, 1973-1974 (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - Misc. Talks, 1968-1969 (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - Misc. Correspondence, 1971-1974 (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - Ground Station Notes, Undated (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - 16 Channel Electronics Notes, 1970-1971 (Box 38, Folder 7)
  - Martin Correspondence, 1969-1970 (Box 38, Folder 8)
  - Misc. Correspondence, 1979-1980 (Box 38, Folder 9)
  - Field-Centers Reports, 1979-1981 (Box 38, Folder 10)
  - Misc. Correspndence, 1979-1981 (Box 38, Folder 11)
  - Astronomy-NAIC Fight Correspondence, 1979 (Box 38, Folder 12)
    Note on folder: "CRAP"
  - Misc. Correspondence and Documents, 1986-1987 (Box 38, Folder 13)
  - 8 Meter Telescope Documents, 1986 (Box 38, Folder 14)
  - Aircraft Correspondence, 1976-1978 (Box 38, Folder 15)
  - Astrophysics Pamphlets, 1978 (Box 38, Folder 16)
  - C-141 Documents, 1976-05 (Box 38, Folder 17)
  - Publication Lists, 1982 (Box 38, Folder 18)
  - Misc. Architecture Documents, 1985-1987 (Box 38, Folder 19)
  - Misc. Correspondence, 1986-1987 (Box 38, Folder 20)
  - Ames Peer Review, 1986-1987 (Box 38, Folder 21)
  - Stockholm Observatory Notes, 1978-1979 (Box 38, Folder 22)
  - Misc. Reports, 1984 (Box 38, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence w/ Byurakan Center, 1975-1976 (Box 38, Folder 24)
  - Misc. Correspondence- Dennis, Undated (Box 38, Folder 25)
  - C-141 Documents, 1975-1977 (Box 38, Folder 26)
  - LEAR Jet Documents, 1975-1977 (Box 38, Folder 27)
  - IRAS (Infrared Astronomical Satellite) Dutch Experiment Description, 1977 (Box 38, Folder 28)
  - Misc. Presentation Documents IRAS (Infrared Astronomical Satellite), 1977-1978 (Box 38, Folder 29)
  - Photoconductor Reports, 1977-1978 (Box 38, Folder 30)
  - Assessment Study of Infrared Detector Arrays, 1978-08 (Box 38, Folder 31)
  - Jet Propulsion Lab Notes and Transparencies, Undated (Box 39, Folder 18)
  - Polaroid Slides, Undated (Box 39)
  - Slides/Negatives, Undated (Box 39, Folder 19)
  - Photos, Undated (Box 39, Folder 20)
  - Photos, Undated (Box 39, Folder 21)
  - Photos, Undated (Box 39, Folder 22)
  - Slides/Negatives, Undated (Box 39, Folder 23)
  - Slides/Negatives, Undated (Box 39, Folder 24)
  - Slides/Negatives, Undated (Box 39, Folder 25)
  - Astrophysics Subcommittee Documents, 1995-07-27-1995-07-28 (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - SSAC (Space Science Advisory Committee) Documents, 1995-07 (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - General NASA Documents, 1995 (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - Photos, 1967 (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - Misc. Photos and Negatives, 1967 (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - Misc. Photos and Negatives, Undated (Box 40, Folder 6)
  - Misc. Photos and Negatives, Undated (Box 40, Folder 7)
  - CAMERA Program Documentation, 1989 (Box 40, Folder 8)
  - Misc. Reports- Bahcall, 1990-07 (Box 40, Folder 9)
  - Misc. Reports- Bahcall, 1990-03 (Box 40, Folder 10)
  - Albuquerque Meeting Materials, 1990 (Box 40, Folder 11)
  - Tucson Meeting Materials, 1990 (Box 40, Folder 12)
  - Misc. - Bahcall Votes, 1990 (Box 40, Folder 13)
  - IR (Infrared?) Panel Materials, 1989 (Box 40, Folder 14)
  - Misc. Pamphlets, 1990 (Box 40, Folder 15)
  - Space Studies Board Meeting Materials, 1989-1990 (Box 40, Folder 16)
  - Space Studies Board Annual Report, 1990 (Box 40, Folder 17)
  - Space Studies Board Reports, 1992-02 (Box 40, Folder 18)
  - Space Studies Board Reports, 1991-11-01 (Box 40, Folder 19)
  - Space Studies Board Meeting Materials, 1990 (Box 40, Folder 20)
  - Space Studies Board Meeting Materials, 1991/01 (Box 40, Folder 21)
  - Space Studies Board Meeting Materials, 1990 (Box 40, Folder 22)
  - ISO (Infrared Space Observatory) Materials, 1986-1988 (Box 40, Folder 23)
  - NSF (National Science Foundation) Proposal, 1989-1991 (Box 40, Folder 24)
  - Senate Advocacy Correspondence, 1990 (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - National Academy of Sciences Materials, 1989 (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - Misc. Meeting Materials, 1989-1990 (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - Astronomy and Astrophysics Survey Committee Materials, 1990-01 (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - Integral Issues Reports, 1992 (Box 42, Folder 17)
  - Aura Board Minutes, 1993-04-15 (Box 42, Folder 18)
  - SSAAC Responses, 1992-11 (Box 42, Folder 19)
  - Astrophysics Subcommittee - AMOW Materials, 1992-10 (Box 42, Folder 20)
  - Astrophysics Subcommittee Materials, 1992 (Box 42, Folder 21)
  - NIRFOS (Near Infrared Faint Object Spectrometer) Materials, 1979-1980 (Box 42, Folder 22)
  - Kitt Peak Documents, 1987-1988 (Box 42, Folder 23)
  - Misc. Documents, 1990 (Box 42, Folder 24)
  - Germany Documents, 1990 (Box 42, Folder 25)
  - IRR Preparation, 1987 (Box 42, Folder 26)
  - IRS (Infrared Spectrometer) Kickoff Review, 1986 (Box 42, Folder 27)
  - Space Studies Review, 1992 (Box 42, Folder 28)
  - SSB (Space Studies Board) on CSSA (?), 1991 (Box 42, Folder 29)
  - Physics Today Papers, 1991 (Box 42, Folder 30)
  - ISO (Infrared Space Observatory) Workshop, 1991-03-15-1991-03-16 (Box 42, Folder 31)
  - FORD Letters, 1975-1977 (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - Chart Room Materials, 1976 (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - HBO(?) Letters, 1972-1974 (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - The Ford Account, 1976 (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - Cornell Observatory, 1972-1974 (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - Specifications for the Hartung Boothroid Observatory, 1976 (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - Contract Document, 1976 (Box 43, Folder 7)
  - Warm Room Addition to Mt. Pleasant Observatory Phase I, 1976 (Box 43, Folder 8)
  - Chart Room Money Statements (Ford), 1977 (Box 43, Folder 9)
  - Materials for Chart Room (Hartung Boothroid Observatory), 1977 (Box 43, Folder 10)
  - Hartung Boothroid Observatory Chart Room Phase II, 1976-1977 (Box 43, Folder 11)
  - Construction, 1977 (Box 43, Folder 12)
  - Hartung Boothroid Observatory, 1976-1978 (Box 43, Folder 13)
  - Astro Mechanics, 1972 (Box 43, Folder 14)
  - Orders and Invoices, 1972 (Box 43, Folder 15)
  - Telescope Design, Undated (Box 43, Folder 16)
  - Telescope Documents, 1970-1979 (Box 43, Folder 17)
  - Com. (?) Telescopes, 1971 (Box 43, Folder 18)
  - Drives Documents, 1972 (Box 43, Folder 19)
  - Dead Letters and Proposals, 1971-1974 (Box 43, Folder 20)
  - Letters, 1975-1976 (Box 43, Folder 21)
  - Letters, 1982 (Box 43, Folder 22)
  - Letters, 1967-1972 (Box 43, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence, 1969-1974 (Box 43, Folder 24)
  - Letters, 1978 (Box 43, Folder 25)
  - Letters, 1976-1977 (Box 43, Folder 26)
  - Letters, 1975-01-1975-06 (Box 43, Folder 27)